Mss.Ms.Coll.137
American Philosophical Society
- III. Works by Mosteller, 1941-2004; 4.5 Linear feet (Box 15-23)
  - Community Reactions to the Concorde: An Assessment of the Trial Period at Dulles Airport, 1977; 129; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
    Committee on Community Reactions to the Concorde, Assembly of Behavioral and Social Sciences, National Research Council
  - Comparison of Results of Meta-Analyses of Randomized Control Trials and Recommendations of Clinical Experts - Treatments for Myocardial Infraction, 1992; Antman, Elliott M.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 17)
    Draft for article for JAMA
    Chalmers, Thomas C., (Thomas Clark), 1917-1995; Kupelnick, Bruce; Lau, Joseph; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006
  - Compensating for Radiation-Related Cancers by Probability of Causation or Assigned Shares, 1987; 227; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
    Invited paper 31.3, 46th session of the ISI. Bulletin of the International Statistical Institute, Proceedings of the 46th Session
  - Concepts under Scrutiny: Discussion, 1989; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
    Proof of chapter from Wachter and Straf (eds.), The Future of Meta-Analysis
  - Continental Classroom's TV Course in Probability and Statistics, 1962-1963; 52; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
    American Statistician, Vol. 16, No. 5
    Quality, Vol. 7, No. 2
    Mathematics Teacher, Vol. 56, No. 6
    Review of the International Statistical Institute, Vol. 31, No. 2
  - Contributions of Secondary School Mathematics to Social Science, 1963; 55; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
    Presented to the Conference on the Role of Applications in a Secondary School Mathematics Curriculum
  - Controversies in Design and Analysis of Clinical Trials, 1983-2000; 187; 2.0 folders; Gilbert, John P.; Kaptchuk, Ted J., 1947-; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
    From Shapiron and Louis (eds.), Clinical Trials: Issues and Approaches. Reprint and annotated copies or original essay written in 1983, and revised essay from 2000.
  - Cooperative Learning in High School and College, 2002-2003; 2.0 folders; Emerson, John D.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
  - Costs, Risks, and Benefits of Surgery, 1977-1980; 136-138; 3.0 folders; Barnes, Benjamin A., b. 1919; Bunker, John P.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17-18)
    Includes notes, related articles by other scholars, correspondence, and copies of three chapters (Progress in Surgery and Anesthesia; The End Result--Quality of LIfe; Summary, Conclusions, and Recommendations). See also, Series I: Barnes, Benjamin A.; Bunker, John P.
  - Critical Thinking in College Students, 2002; 355; Boes, Lisa; Emerson, John D.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    Educational Media and Technology Yearbook, Vol. 27
  - Cumulative Meta-Analysis of Therapeutic Trials for Myocardial Infraction, 1992; 277; Antman, Elliott M.; Lau, Joseph; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 18)
    Manuscript draft of paper printed in New England Journal of Medicine, Vol. 327, No. 4
  - Data-Analytic Look at US Professional Football Scores, 1971 and 1972, Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
  - Data Analysis, Including Statistics, 1968; 72; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Tukey, John W., (John Wilder), 1915-2000 (Box 18)
    Chapter 10 in Revised Handbook of Social Psychology, Lindzey and Aronson, editors.
  - Description or Prediction?, 1984; 195; Hoaglin, David C. (David Caster), 1944-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    Reprinted from the 1984 Business and Economic Statistics Section, Proceedings of the American Statistical Association.
  - Development Programs for College Faculty: Preparing for the 21st Century, 1999; 347; Emerson, John D.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    Manuscript and reprint from Branch and Fitzgerald (eds.), Educational Media and Technology Yearbook 2000
  - Discussion of Statistical Aspects of Rain Stimulation, 1970; 80; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    Review of the International Statiscal Institute, Vol. 38
  - Disputed Authorship: The Federalist Papers, 1985; 203; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Wallace, David L. (David Lee), 1928- (Box 18)
    From Andrews and Herzberg (eds.), A Collection of Problems from Many Fields for the Student and Research Worker
  - Education Studies that Intervene: Findings from a Five-Year Census of Two Top-Tier Education Journals, 2000-2003; Miech, Edward J.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Nave, Bill (Box 18)
    Notes, correspondence, manuscript drafts
  - Edward Kass. Faculty of Medicine - Memorial Minute, 1993; 292; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    Harvard Gazette. July 9, 1993
  - Errors: Nonsampling Errors, 1968; 69, 143; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1968.
    From Kruskal and Tanur (eds.), International Encyclopedia of Statistics, Vol. 1 (Free Press, 1978).
  - Experimental Methods: Clinical Trials, 1991; 252; McKneally, Martin F.; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Neugebauer, E. A. M. (Box 18)
    From Troidl et al (eds.), Principles and Practice of Research: Strategies for Surgical Investigators
  - Experimentation and Innovations, 1977; 132; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    Proceedings of the 41st Session of the International Statistical Institute
  - Facilitating Scholarship: Creating the Atmosphere, Setting, and Teamwork for Research, 1986; 212; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 18)
  - Few Interventions, Fewer Trials: Why Research Design Makes a Difference in Education, 2003-2004; 2.0 folders; Miech, Edward J.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Nave, Bill (Box 18)
  - Few Rapid Computational Methods, 1947; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    Presented at the joint meeting of the Eastern Psychological Association and the Institute of Mathematical Statistics, April 1947
  - Foreign Language Translations, 1961-1990; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    Assorted copies of title pages from foreign language translations of Mosteller's work.
  - Foreward, 1961; 49; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    From Edmund Berkeley, Probability and Statistics: An Introduction through Experiments
  - Foreward, 1975; 120; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    From Philip Houser, Social Statistics in Use
  - Formulating an Initial Research Plan, 1998; 251, 336; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 18)
    Two reprints: From Troidl et al (eds.), Principles and Practice of Research: Strategies for Surgical Investigators.
  - Fourth Quarter of the Super Bowl, 1993; 283; Cooper, Harris; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    National Academy of Sciences, Office of News and Public Information, January 1993
  - From Martinson to Meta-Analysis: The Interaction Between Evidence and Policy in Crime Reduction Policy, Circa 2003; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
  - Gambling Systems, n.d.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
  - Guide to Probability and Statistics, 1961; 48; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Noether, Gottfried E., (Gottfried Emanuel) (Box 18)
  - Helen K. Mosteller, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Henry K. Beecher, 1978; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 18)
    Harvard Gazette, January 1978
  - How Big is Big, How Rare is Rare? Inquiring Minds Want to Know, 1986; 220; Culliton, Barbara J.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
    Science Writer, Vol. 34, No. 3
  - How Many You Need Depends on What is Already Known: Estimating the Size of Future Randomized Control Trials Based on Meta-Analysis, 1992; Chalmers, Thomas C., (Thomas Clark), 1917-1995; Lau, Joseph; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 18)
  - How Medical Professionals Evaluate Expressions for Probabilities, 1985-1987; Barnett, G. Octo; Kong, Augustine; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 18)
    Manuscript copies; reprint from New England Journal of Medicine, Vol. 315; letters by Robert Timothy Reagan and Thomas Wallsten; letters to editor regarding the article printed in the New England Journal of Medicine, Vol. 316.
  - How Science Writers and Others Quantify Expressions of Probability: A Proposed Codification, 1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 19)
  - How to Think about the New Math and the Old Math, 1974; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
  - Ideas about Statistical Significance Tests and Confidence Statements, 1979; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
  - Ideas of Bias, 1985; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
  - Ideas of Representative Sampling, 1981; 174; Kruskal, William, 1919-2005; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
    From D. Fiske (ed.), New Directions for Methodology of Social and Behavioral Science: Problems with Language Imprecision, vol. 9.
  - Illustrative Calculations of Probabilities of Winning from a Given Position, 1991; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
  - Imperfect Science of Victim Compensation, 197; Jarmal, David; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
  - Implications of Measures of Quality of Life for Policy Development, 1986-1987; 217; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
    Manuscript draft and reprint from Journal of Chronic Diseases, Vol. 40, No. 6
  - Improving Research Methodology: An Overview, 1990; 247; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
    From Secrest et al (eds.), Research Methodology: Strengthening Causal Interpretations of Nonexperimental Data
  - Incidence of Gallbladder Disease in Obese Women, 1993; Chalmers, Thomas C., (Thomas Clark), 1917-1995; Klawansky, Sidney; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Shah, Nirav; Zachery, Clarence (Box 19)
  - Inference in an Authorship Problem, 1962-1963; 53; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Wallace, David L. (David Lee), 1928- (Box 19)
    Manuscript draft and annotated reprint from American Statistical Association Journal, June 1963
  - Innovation and Evaluation, 1981; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
    Presidential Address, 147th Annual Meeting, AAAS
  - Introductory Biostatistics Texts: Selected Annotated Bibliography, 1998; 335; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Rosner, Bernard, (Bernard A.) (Box 19)
  - John Davis Williams, 1909-1964. In Memoriam, 1964-1965; 56; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
  - John Parker Gilbert, 1926-1980, 1982; 176; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
    Includes booklet comemorating Gilbert's memorial service and reprint from American Statistician, Vol. 36, No. 1
  - Kenneth Prewitt, Frederick Mosteller, and Herbert A. Simon Testify at National Science Foundation Hearings, 1980; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Prewitt, Kenneth; Simon, Herbert A., (Herbert Alexander), 1916-2001 (Box 19)
    Items, Vol. 34, No. 1
  - Laminectomy and the Treatment of Lower-Back Pain in Massachusetts, 1992-1993; 288; Hedley-Whyte, John; Milamed, Debra R.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Warfield, Carol A. (Box 19)
    Manuscript copy and reprint. International Journal of Technology Assessment in Health Care, Vol. 9, No. 3
  - Lapse in Standards: Linking Standards-Based Reform with Student Achievement, 1998-2000; 350; Miech, Edward J.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Nave, Bill (Box 19)
    Notes, manuscript drafts, correspondence, and reprint from Phi Delta Kappan, October 2000
  - Large-Scale Professional Development for Schoolteachers: Cases from Pittsburgh, New York City, and the National School Reform Faculty, 2000-2001; 353; Miech, Edward J.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Nave, Bill (Box 19)
    Correspondence and reprint from New Directions for Evaluation, Vol. 2001, No. 90
  - Leonard Jimmie Savage Memorial Service Tribute, Yale University, March 18, 1972, 1981; 167; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
    From Ericson (ed.), The Writings of Leonard Jimmie Savage--A Memorial Selection
  - Lessons from Sports Statistics, 1996-1997; 331, 333; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
    From 1996 Proceedings of the Section on Statistics in Sports, American Statistical Association.
    American Statistician, Vol. 51, No. 4
  - Loran Commission: A Summary Report, 1988; 236; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 19)
    Harvard Community Health Plan, 1988 Annual Report
  - Master of Arts Thesis, 1941; 4.0 folders; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
  - Mathematical Models for Behavior Theory: A Brief Report on an Interuniversity Summer Research Seminar, 1951; 20a; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
  - Mathematical Sciences and Social Sciences: Excerpts from the Report of a Panel of the Behavioral and Social Sciences Survey, 1970-1971; 83; Kruskal, William, 1919-2005; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 19)
    Items, Vol. 24, No. 3.
    American Statistician, Vol. 25, No. 1
  - Measuring Outcome from Anesthesia and Operation, 1985; 204; Gasko-Green, Miriam; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    Manuscript draft and reprint from Theoretical Surgery, Vol. 1
  - Measuring the Quality of Life, 1976; Gilbert, John P.; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    From Surgery in the United States, vol. 3
  - Messages from the President, 1992-1993; 273, 280, 284, 290; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    Brief messages written by Mosteller in the ISI Newsletter, Vol. 16-17.
  - Meta-Analysis of Randomized Trials, 1999; 344; Berkey, Catherine S.; Colditz, Graham A.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    From Hennekens et al (eds.), Clinical Trials in Cardiovascular Disease
  - Methods for Interpreting and Combining Experimental Results, 1988; Laird, Nan M., 1943-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
  - Minor Works, 1943-1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
  - Modeling Pitcher Performance and the Distribution of Runs per Inning in Major League Baseball, 1996; 326; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Rosner, Bernard, (Bernard A.); Youtz, Cleo (Box 20)
    Manuscript copy and reprint from The American Statistician, Vol 50, No. 4.
  - Moriguti Report on the Role of Statisticians: A Discussion, 1994; 302; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    ISI Occasional Paper Series #4
  - Mozart's Random Music, 1968; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 20)
  - Muddiest Point in the Lecture as a Feedback Device, 1992; 282; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    From Medianen. In Swedish and English.
  - National Halothane Study. A Study of the Possible Association between Halothane Anesthesia and Postoperative Hepatic Necrosis, 1969; Bunker, John P.; Forrest, William H.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Vandam, Leroy D. (Box 20)
  - New Statistical Methods in Public Policy I and II: Experimentation. Exploratory Data Analysis, 1979; 149-150; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Mosteller, Gale, 1953- (Box 20)
    Journal of Contemporary Business, Vol. 8, No. 3
  - Notes on an Authorship Problem, 1962; 51; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Wallace, David L. (David Lee), 1928- (Box 20)
    From Proceedings of a Harvard Symposium on Digital Computers and their Applications
  - Notes on Cooperative Learning, 1996; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Olson, Marjorie; Youtz, Cleo (Box 20)
  - On CALL: A Review of Computer-Assisted Language Learning in US Colleges and Universities, 1997; 328; Miech, Edward J.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Nave, Bill (Box 20)
    From Branch and Minor (eds.), Educational Media and Technology Yearbook 1997
  - Patient-controlled Analgesia in the Postoperative Patient: Meta-Analyses of Initial Randomized Control Trials, 1992; Ballantyne, Jane, 1948-; Carr, Daniel B.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    Manuscript draft
  - Practical Applications of New Theory - A Review, 1949-1950; 13; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Tukey, John W., (John Wilder), 1915-2000 (Box 20)
    Parts I-IV from Industrial Quality Control, Vol 6, No. 2-5.
  - Predicting Professional Sports Game Outcomes from Intermediate Game Scores, 1992; 281; Cooper, Harris; DeNeve, Kristina M.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    Manuscript draft and reprint from Chance, Vol. 5, No. 3-4
  - Principles and Practice of Surgical Research - Strategies for Surgical Investigations, 1989; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    Includes notes and correspondence
  - Principles of Sampling, 1954; 30; Cochran, William G., (William Gemmell), 1909-1980; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Tukey, John W., (John Wilder), 1915-2000 (Box 20)
    Reprint in English from Journal of the American Statistical Association, Vol. 49; and in Spanish from Estadistica, Vol. 14, No. 51
  - Problems of Omission in Communications, 1979; 146; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics, Vol. 25, No. 5
  - Professional Golf Scores are Poisson on the Final Tournament Days, 1992; 287; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 20)
    Manuscript drafts and reprint from 1992 Proceedings of the Section on Statistics in Sports, American Statistical Association.
  - Progress Report on Statistics in the Biomedical Sciences and Research into Statistical Practice and the Development of Educational Means to Improve the Practice, 1982; Bailar, John C., (John Christian), 1904-1991; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Relman, Arnold S., 1923- (Box 20)
    Progress report for Project RF 79-026, the Rockefeller Foundation
  - Project on Mathematical Models, Memoranda, Circa 1952; 4.0 folders (Box 20)
    - E. Some Problems in Determining Maxims of Functions of Several Variables, Circa 1952; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    - F. Testing the Goodness of a Fit of a Social Interaction Matrix, Circa 1952; Heinicke, Christoph M., (Christoph Mathew), 1926- (Box 20)
    - G. Remarks on Stephan's Distribution of Social Interaction, Circa 1952; Bailyn, Lotte; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    - H. Some Problems in Determining Maxima of Functions of Several Variables, Circa 1952; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
  - Prospect of Data-based Medicine in the Light of ECPC, 1993; 294; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    Manuscript copy, annotated proof, and reprint. Milbank Quarterly, Vol. 71, No. 3
  - Quality of Life Lecture, n.d.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
    Original folder labeled: " Menlo Park, Kaiser, Q of L"
  - Quantifying Probability Expressions: What is the Probability of a Likely Event?, 1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 20)
  - Quantitative Meanings of Verbal Probability Expressions, 1987-1988; 2.0 folders; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Reagan, Robert Timothy; Youtz, Cleo (Box 20-21)
    Manuscript drafts and correspondence
  - Randomized Clinical Trials in Surgery, 1988-1989; 242; 2.0 folders; McKneally, Martin F.; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    Manuscript copies and reprint from International Journal of Technology Assessment in Health Care, Vol. 5, No. 3
  - Recommendations for the Training of Teachers of Mathematics, 1961; Mathematical Association of America.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
  - Relationship of NACEEO's Recommendations to the Concerns Expressed by the Congress after Completing a Major Oversight Study of ESAA in 1977 and Developing Legislation to Change the ESAA Program, 1978; 140; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 21)
  - Remarks by Frederick Mosteller on the Occasion of a Grand Banquet Celebrating the 40th Anniversary of the Department of Statistics and the 70th Birthday of William H. Kruskal, 1989; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
  - Report of the Evaluation Committee on the University of Chicago Department of Statistics, 1970-1971; 94; Anscombe, Francis John; Blackwell, David, 1919-2010; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    University of Chicago Record, Vol. 4, No. 5
    American Statistician, June 1971
  - Report of the President, 1975; 121; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    Institute of Mathematics Statistics Bulletin, Vol. 4, No. 6
  - Reporting Clinical Trials in General Surgical Journals, 1984; 189; Emerson, John D.; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    Surgery, Vol. 95, No. 5
  - Resistant Adjusted Analysis of the 1971 and 1972 Regular Professional Football Schedule, 1973; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
  - Resistant Analysis of 1971 and 1972 Professional Football, 1979; 144; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    From Goldstein (ed.), Sports, Games, and Play: Social and Psychological Viewpoints
  - Response of Frederick Mosteller, 1997; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    Manuscript concerning standards of mathematics taught at the high school level.
  - Review of DHEW's Research Planning Principles, 1979; Institute of Medicine. (U.S.); London, Irving M.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 21)
  - Review of the Academic Impact of Youth Anti-Violence Programs, Circa 2003; 2.0 folders; Falotico-Taylor, Jennifer; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    Two manuscript drafts.
  - Role of Field Trials in Evaluating School Practices: A Rare Design, 1998-2000; 351; Miech, Edward J.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Nave, Bill (Box 21)
    Manuscript and reprint from Stufflebeam et al (eds.), Evaluation Models: Viewpoints on Educational and Human Services Evaluation, 2nd edition
  - Role of Statistics in Medical Research, 1981-1982; 184; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    Manuscript copy and reprint from Mike and Stanley (eds.), Statistics in Medical Research: Methods and Issues, with Applications in Cancer Research
  - Role of the Social Science Research Council in the Advance of Mathematics in the Social Sciences, 1974; 115; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    Items, Vol. 28, No. 2
  - Runaways: A Review of the Literature, Circa 1998; Falotico-Taylor, Jennifer; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
  - Sampling Inspection, 1948; 7; Freeman, Harvey A.; Friedman, Milton, 1912-2006; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    Copies of Chapters 3-6, Appendix to Part II
  - Samuel Stanley Wilks, 1968-1970; 70; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 21)
    Includes reprint from International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1968, and Introduction to the First Samuel Stanley Wilks Memorial Lecture, 1970.
  - Scoring Scheme for Picking Good Examples, Problems, and Test Questions, 1987; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 22)
  - Selected Quantitative Techniques, 1954; 32; Bush, Robert R.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 22)
    From Handbook of Social Psychology, Gardner Lindzey, ed.
  - Smaller Classes Do Make a Difference in the Early Grades, 1997; 332; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 22)
    Harvard Education Letter, July/August 1997
  - Social Programs, 1980; 161; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 22)
    Society, Vol. 17, No. 6
  - Social Science Research Council Committee on Statistical Training, 1967; 65; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Taeuber, Conrad, 1906-1999; Webbink, Paul, 1903-1973 (Box 22)
    American Statistician, December 1967
    Items, December 1967
  - Some Common Misunderstandings and their Cures: Easily Corrected Statistical Blunders, 1971; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 22)
  - Some Considerations on the Role of Probability and Statistics in the School Mathematics Programs of the 1970s, 90; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 22)
    Manuscript and printed copy. From School Mathematics Study Group, Report of a Conference on Responsibilities for School Mathematics in the 70s
  - Some Evaluation Needs, 1993; 298; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 22)